Cláudio Rodrigues

Date of birth: 26/08/1998 | **Nationality:** Portuguese, British | (+351) 964039199 |

claudioduarterodrigues@gmail.com | claudio.duarte.98@live.com.pt | https://duarterodrigues.pt/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/cláudio-rodrigues-5263551a8/ GitHub: https://github.com/claudiorodr

About me:

I'm a computer science student from Portugal, I am 24 years old and I'm an enthusiast of technology, specially everything software related. I have developed several open-source projects, either in my course or free time, most of them are available on my GitHub page with their description. Here you'll find more information about me, expertise, projects, and people I've worked with.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/03/2022 - CURRENT - Porto, Portugal

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - UNTILE

- Developed next-generation web applications using Next.js, TypeScript, GraphQL and RESTful web services:
- Discussed ideas with both team and/or clients to create the best possible solutions;
- Worked within a well-opinionated technology stack, with developer tools and methodologies;
- Helped in the creation of in-house patterns;

28/02/2021 - 02/2022 - Funchal, Portugal

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER - ELGORITHM

- Build innovative online marketplace platform in the tourism sector.
- Remote collaborating in a small team with innovative ideas.
- Development of high-performance web application using React and Node.is.
- Involved in CI/CD pipeline automation processes for build and deploy.
- Performed bug fixes and code reviews.

31/01/2021 - 27/02/2022 - Funchal, Portugal

TECHNICAL RESEARCH ASSISTANT - MARE-MADEIRA

- Applied technical skills to design and implement synergies for the development of new technologies and methodologies in marine ecology and biogeography, with a special emphasis in insular ecosystems.
- Optimized a variety of laboratory protocols and experiments with the help of software automation tools.
- Organized and prioritize daily laboratory tasks to fulfill established research aims.

01/01/2020 - 30/03/2020 - Funchal, Portugal

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER - ARDITI

Collaboration with other members of an interdisciplinary team, including marine biologists from the Oceanic Observatory of Madeira, developing cross-platform mobile applications in order to collect and export dive data, for further analysis on migrations of marine species on the island of Madeira.

01/07/2019 - 31/07/2019 - Funchal, Portugal

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER - M-ITI

Summer internship promoted by the Regional Department of Education and Sport, through the performance of functions in the area of Computer Engineering, at the Madeira Interactive Technologies Institute, in the periods from July 2nd to August 1st, 2019 in a total of 132 hours.

Business or Sector Professional, scientific and technical activities

Address Caminho da Penteada, Polo Cientifico e Tecnologico da Madeira, floor -2, 9020-105, Funchal, Portugal

Website https://www.m-iti.org

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

25/09/2020 - 09/2021 - Funchal, Portugal

MASTER'S DEGREE - Universidade da Madeira

- Distributed systems
- Network-centric applications
- Artificial Intelligence and Game Design
- Software Design and Implementation
- Software Architectures
- Ubiquitous computing
- Security in Communication Systems
- Decision Support Systems

Address Rua Dos Ferreiros, Funchal, Portugal | Website https://www.uma.pt/ | Final grade 19 |

Level in EQF EQF level 7 | **Thesis** Exploiting IoT-enabled Inertial Sensores

24/03/2020 - 01/07/2020 - Maribor, Slovenia

ERASMUS PROGRAMME – Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, University of Maribor

Address Koroška cesta 46, Maribor, Slovenia | Website https://feri.um.si/en/

13/09/2016 - 27/06/2019 - Funchal, Portugal

BACHLOR'S DEGREE - University of Madeira

- Operating Systems
- Object Oriented Programming
- Database Management Systems
- Calculation I
- Data Structure and Algorithms
- Theory and Fundamentals of Computing
- Computing Architecture
- Introduction to Electronics
- Mechanics and Waves
- Networks and Data Communication
- Digital systems
- Requirements Engineering

Address Rua Dos Ferreiros, Funchal, Portugal | Website https://www.uma.pt/

Field of study Information and Communication Technologies | Level in EQF EQF level 6

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **PORTUGUESE**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	B2	B2	C1	B2
NORWEGIAN	A2	A1	A1	A1	A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Python | JavaScript | Git | NodeJS | Linux | RESTful Api | MySQL | React js | Next.js | Javascript ES6 / Typescript

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: A1
Driving Licence: B1
Driving Licence: B